<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Your House</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-12-02_entry492/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-12-02_entry492/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;287&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; title=&#34;VashonCodeRecomendations (Medium)&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 3px 3px; border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;VashonCodeRecomendations (Medium)&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/492/Open-Live-Writer-50177a361c6b_8E09-VashonCodeRecomendations_(Medium)_eae36949-1e16-45ef-823e-b35e135bf453.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;There is a new tool available to look at how to enhance your house’s chance of surviving future earthquakes, winter storms, and flooding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GET READY TO SHAKEOUT!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-10-14_entry491/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 15:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-10-14_entry491/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Drop, Cover, Hold On&#34; src=&#34;https://www.shakeout.org/images/dropcoverholdon_eng_white.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year&#39;s International ShakeOut Day is October 20, when millions of people worldwide will participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mil.wa.gov/earthquake&#34;&gt;earthquake&lt;/a&gt; drills at work, school, or home!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat Wave Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-07-28_entry490/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-07-28_entry490/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that the National Weather Service Excessive Heat Warning has been extended through Saturday, the heat safety tips are even more important. The following tips have been compiled from multiple sources by the Vashon Emergency Operations Center and VashonBePrepared, in collaboration with Vashon Island Fire &amp;amp; Rescue.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stay hydrated. Drink plenty of water before you feel thirsty.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ideally, stay indoors and out of the heat of the day, generally from midday to early evening.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If your job requires you to work outside, do what you can to work in the shade and be especially mindful of getting plenty of water, taking breaks in the shade or in a cool space, and avoiding sunburn. Try to perform critical outdoor tasks in the morning only.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can keep your home cooler by shutting blinds, drawing curtains, and keeping windows closed while outdoor temperatures are higher than indoor temperatures. Of course, use fans or air-conditioners, if you have them. Once outdoor temperatures drop below indoor temperatures, open your windows and cross-ventilate to cool down your house.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be neighborly. Check on your neighbors, friends, and family in the area – particularly seniors and people with medical conditions – to ensure they are not suffering from heat illness at home.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Signs of &lt;b&gt;heat exhaustion&lt;/b&gt; are heavy sweating; weakness; cold, pale, and clammy skin; weak pulse; fainting; vomiting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Signs of &lt;b&gt;heat stroke&lt;/b&gt; are high body temperature (103F or higher); hot, dry skin; rapid and strong pulse; possible unconsciousness. Heat stroke is a medical emergency - call 911 and take measures to cool the person down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Never leave children or pets in a vehicle. During extreme heat, temperatures inside cars can skyrocket in minutes to deadly levels.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you are taking your dog for walks, don&#39;t overexert them or yourself. Make sure you and your pet are taking in plenty of water.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you are headed to the beach or pool, keep a close eye on kids to prevent drowning. &lt;b&gt;Drowning is fast. Silent. Preventable.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Know how to spot the signs of a person drowning. They:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usually cannot call for help&lt;li&gt;Usually cannot wave their arms&lt;li&gt;May be vertical in the water&lt;li&gt;May look like they are climbing a ladder&lt;li&gt;Their mouth may bob above and below the water&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warning/Cooling Centers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-07-28_entry489/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-07-28_entry489/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Excessive Heat Warning issued by the National Weather Service has been extended one more day through Saturday evening. High temperatures over the next several days are forecast in the range of 90 to 94 degrees. There will be relief overnight as temperatures fall into the low sixties.&lt;p&gt;The National Weather Service classifies this as a level three heat risk event out of a possible four levels in the National Weather Service classification system. Level three means the heat is a high risk for much of the population, especially those who are heat-sensitive and those without effective cooling or adequate hydration.&lt;p&gt;VashonBePrepared and the Vashon Emergency Operations Center, in collaboration with Vashon Island Fire &amp;amp; Rescue, have worked with community partners to open two cooling centers on Vashon and they will continue in operation with some changes in opening hours.&lt;p&gt;Vashon Public Library will be open today from 10:00 am to 5:00 pm. The library is at Ober Park, 17210 Vashon Highway SW.&lt;p&gt;Vashon Center for the Arts will be open from 1:00 pm to 7:00 pm. VCA is at the intersection of Vashon Highway and Cemetery Road, 19600 Vashon Highway SW.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Northwest Citizen Corps Expo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-06-15_entry488/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-06-15_entry488/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1&gt;September 17-18 at Yakima Valley Community College&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Save the date!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Willie Nunn Sworn-In as FEMA Region 10 Administrator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-03-07_entry487/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 23:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-03-07_entry487/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;354&#34; height=&#34;292&#34; title=&#34;clip_image002&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px; border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;clip_image002&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/487/Open-Live-Writer-e6af091e4086_D39B-clip_image002_32d2e6bd-4b33-4125-8bb8-7858f9fca367.gif&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; hspace=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOTHELL, Wash&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp; -&amp;nbsp; FEMA Region 10 welcomed its new Regional Administrator, Willie G. Nunn, following his appointment by President Joe Biden. Mr. Nunn was sworn in by FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell at the regional office this morning.&amp;nbsp; &lt;p&gt;As the Regional Administrator, Mr. Nunn will lead and coordinate all activities in support of FEMA’s mission with the states of Alaska, Idaho, Oregon, and Washington, as well as the 271 federally recognized tribes within the region. &lt;p&gt;Mr. Nunn joined FEMA in June 2007 and has effectively managed disasters in all four states in Region 10 plus nine states across the country and two United States territories. He was certified as a Type 1 Federal Coordinating Officer (FCO) in June 2014. As an FCO, Mr. Nunn served as the representative of the President of the U.S., Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, and FEMA Administrator during major disaster and emergency declarations.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;347&#34; height=&#34;369&#34; title=&#34;clip_image004&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;clip_image004&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/487/Open-Live-Writer-e6af091e4086_D39B-clip_image004_53660fad-d06b-47ea-95d7-b46e0aae2a7d.gif&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; hspace=&#34;12&#34;&gt;His previous roles within FEMA included serving as Assistant Director of the Office of Federal Disaster Coordination, as Lead Field Coordinator for FEMA Region 10, and as an FCO Type 1 Field Leader Supervisor for FEMA Regions 2, 8, 9, and 10. He also served as Acting Deputy Assistant Administrator for Insurance, Acting Deputy Assistant Administrator for the Field Operations Directorate, and Senior Advisor for the Operational Coordination Division.&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining FEMA, Mr. Nunn was on active duty for over 26 years in the U.S. Air Force, retiring as a Colonel. His assignments included two command tours and two combat tours in Operations Enduring Freedom in 2002 in Afghanistan and Iraqi Freedom in 2003.&amp;nbsp; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Nunn earned a Bachelor of Arts in History from the University of Alabama-Birmingham and a Master of Public Administration from the University of Oklahoma. He and his wife Sylvia have three children, Sacha, Adam, and Alene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional Citizen Corps Unite!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-02-10_entry486/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 21:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-02-10_entry486/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:HinaKilioni@rentonwa.gov&#34;&gt;Hina Kilioni&lt;/a&gt; and I just had a great chat on a whole range of topics, but most significantly on his desire to facilitate communications among regional disaster organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research and Information Needs to Improve Healthcare Access in Disasters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-02-10_entry485/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 20:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-02-10_entry485/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cascadiacopeshub.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;393&#34; height=&#34;184&#34; title=&#34;cascadiacopeshub_org&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;cascadiacopeshub_org&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/485/Open-Live-Writer-8aae92d36692_B0BB-cascadiacopeshub_org_0d164f71-397e-4968-a4a1-625778eb9ac6.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We are writing to invite you to share your input and expertise in a virtual forum hosted by the Cascadia Coastlines and People Research Coordination Network (Cascadia CoPe RCN) on “Research and Information Needs to Improve Healthcare Access in Disasters.” This event is part of a broader effort to advance research on coastal hazards and resilience that will be useful to coastal communities in the Pacific Northwest, coordinated by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cascadiacopeshub.org/&#34;&gt;Cascadia Coastlines and Peoples Hub&lt;/a&gt; (Cascadia CoPes Hub). You can learn more about our work &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1OYGQ-7Itm2QRdq210TfbkZDoI06u2TRX/view&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The forum will be held by Zoom on March 2, 2022 from 9am - 11am PST.&amp;nbsp; Please register by our priority registration deadline of February 23, 2022&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://washington.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJwqdeqhpzMoGNLYWHKk01oOP5EC5yNMThq8&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt; [here]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;to receive the Zoom link. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coastal communities are among those most at risk of disruptions to healthcare access in the event of an earthquake or other natural hazard. In response, our virtual forum will bring together practitioners and scientists interested in collaboration to improve healthcare access following major disasters resulting from natural hazards in coastal communities to:&lt;p&gt;1. Identify information needed to better understand healthcare access impacts and prevent disruptions within Cascadia coastal communities following disasters resulting from natural hazards;&lt;p&gt;2. To develop a collaborative research agenda, based on community priorities, to inform and improve healthcare access following major disasters resulting from natural hazards in coastal communities.&lt;p&gt;The virtual forum will be space for Pacific Northwest coastal emergency managers, public health officials, healthcare coalitions, hospital emergency managers, healthcare service providers/administrators, transportation planners, local elected officials, public safety (police/fire/EMS), and community planners to share their insights and expertise.&amp;nbsp; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please share this invitation with your colleagues with relevant responsibilities or expertise&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;, particularly those from small and medium sized healthcare organizations serving PNW coastal communities (e.g., skilled nursing facilities, opioid treatment programs, federally qualified health centers, etc.). &lt;/i&gt;Please note that we are planning to host a separate forum at a later date specifically for tribal representatives.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We understand that your time is limited. To thank you for your sharing your time and expertise with us during the forum, we are offering an honorarium. Please contact Jessica Nagtalon (&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;i&gt;nagtalon@uw.edu&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;) for more information about the honorarium.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please let us know if you have any questions or concerns. We look forward to working with you.&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deohs.washington.edu/faculty/nicole-errett&#34;&gt;Nicole Errett&lt;/a&gt;, Forum organizing committee chair &lt;br&gt;with support from: &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ess.washington.edu/people/profile.php?pid=schmidt--david&#34;&gt;David Schmidt&lt;/a&gt;, PI Cascadia CoPe RCN&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ceoas.oregonstate.edu/people/peter-ruggiero&#34;&gt;Peter Ruggiero&lt;/a&gt;, PI Cascadia CoPes Hub &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evans.uw.edu/profile/ann-bostrom/&#34;&gt;Ann Bostrom&lt;/a&gt;, Co-PI Cascadia CoPes Hub and Cascadia CoPe RCN</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Wood Framed Homes from Earthquakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-01-14_entry484/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2022/2022-01-14_entry484/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;174&#34; title=&#34;image&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/484/Open-Live-Writer-Protecting-Wood-Framed-Homes-from-Earthq_874A-image_7acddce0-39c9-4ed6-bc00-7da0046aa1f6.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;MyBuildingPermit and Simpson Strong-tie have partnered to provide a series of free home retrofit classes for homeowners and contractors.&amp;nbsp; &lt;p&gt;The virtual class highlights WABO’s newly revised &lt;a href=&#34;https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwabo.memberclicks.net%2Fassets%2FEmergency_Mngt%2FFEMA-WA%2520061421%2520-%2520Earthquake%2520Home%2520Retrofit%2520Plan%2520Set%2520-%2520WABO%2520Stamp.pdf&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Ccynthia.foley%40kingcounty.gov%7Cb603df56a11e43e6068908d9d5e6960d%7Cbae5059a76f049d7999672dfe95d69c7%7C0%7C0%7C637776009512295124%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;amp;sdata=Moifqu7s3VwxpVG2yAr%2FYcOL8rHG9ayx9VDPqUk0nOY%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&#34;&gt;seismic retrofit standard plans&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; All classes are free and pre-registration is required. Classes are being offered at the following dates and times:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, February 9, 2022 at 12:00 PM to 1:00 PM&lt;li&gt;Thursday, February 10, 2022 at 6:00 PM to 7:30 PM&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, March 9, 2022 at 12:00 PM to 1:00 PM&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, March 16, 2022 at 6:00 PM to 7:30 PM&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To register, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fmybuildingpermit.com%2Ftraining&amp;amp;data=04%7C01%7Ccynthia.foley%40kingcounty.gov%7Cb603df56a11e43e6068908d9d5e6960d%7Cbae5059a76f049d7999672dfe95d69c7%7C0%7C0%7C637776009512295124%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;amp;sdata=goYEGRjDH%2FuBJCGFFixDZZpi5z9fPUbhHIhZ6wk8UKA%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&#34;&gt;MBP Training website&lt;/a&gt; and select the preferred date and time.&amp;nbsp; Registrants will receive a webinar link prior to class start.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;606&#34; height=&#34;218&#34; title=&#34;image&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/484/Open-Live-Writer-Protecting-Wood-Framed-Homes-from-Earthq_874A-image_0ff29853-16b4-4a6c-a2bc-ce2bd9a88b5d.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
