<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disaster Preparedness--  Free September 23 Seminar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-09-11_entry403/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-09-11_entry403/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./images/403/Windows-Live-Writer-314d9ffc3297_7C40-image_4.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;image&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px none; background-image: none; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; display: inline; padding-right: 0px; float: right;&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;./images/403/Windows-Live-Writer-314d9ffc3297_7C40-image_thumb_1.png&#34; width=&#34;371&#34; height=&#34;261&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field Day 2017-- This Saturday with a New Location!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-06-18_entry402/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 20:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-06-18_entry402/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./images/402/Windows-Live-Writer-3ad8f7cf11a4_B9D8-clip_image002_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;clip_image002&#34; style=&#34;border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px; background-image: none; border-bottom: 0px; float: right; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: inline; padding-right: 0px&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; hspace=&#34;12&#34; alt=&#34;clip_image002&#34; src=&#34;./images/402/Windows-Live-Writer-3ad8f7cf11a4_B9D8-clip_image002_thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;398&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; height=&#34;618&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Vashon Maury Island Radio Club and VashonBePrepared invites the public to visit Vashon’s amateur radio volunteers at this Saturday’s 2017 Field Day event!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Managers Announce Improvements After Cascadia Rising Exercise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-06-07_entry401/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 17:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-06-07_entry401/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;float: right; margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px; display: inline&#34; alt=&#34;The Cascadia Subduction Zone off the coast of North America spans from northern California to southern British Columbia.&#34; src=&#34;https://www.fema.gov/media-library-data/1459793872818-e5eb3428c609347ac6694298128b8d42/map_cascadia_subduction_zone_medium.jpg&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; height=&#34;257&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEATTLE – &lt;/strong&gt;A year following one of the nation’s largest domestic drills, lessons-learned continue to guide strategies that improve the Pacific Northwest’s ability to survive and recover from a catastrophic Cascadia Subduction Zone (CSZ) earthquake and tsunami.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Budget Blueprint Cuts $667M of Emergency and Disaster Funding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-03-16_entry400/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-03-16_entry400/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this is still evolving, the initial blueprint of the federal budget has the following language:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NWS Web Site Changing For The Better – March 7th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-02-24_entry399/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 19:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-02-24_entry399/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Your Bookmarks Will Need To Change Too!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The National Weather Service’s primary web site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weather.gov&#34;&gt;www.weather.gov&lt;/a&gt; plans to implement an upgrade. The improvement will involve the point ‘n click site specific forecasts and zone forecasts. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vashon Maury Island Radio Club Sponsors Amateur Radio Technician&#39;s License Prep &amp; Test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-02-21_entry398/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-02-21_entry398/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Date: May 5th, 6th, 7th. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Hours: 5th - 6PM to 9PM, 6th - 9AM to 5PM, 7th - 10AM to 3PM. Testing will start at 3PM.** &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community Emergency Response Team (CERT) Training Class</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-01-25_entry397/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-01-25_entry397/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emergency Preparedness &amp;amp; Response:&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;A Half Day Basic Class on February 4 &amp;hellip; OR &amp;hellip;A 45-hour Course Packed With Skills &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Participation in CERT is highly rewarding for both you and your neighbors. If community support when problems arise is important to you, CERT will likely be an extraordinarily positive experience.  CERT originated in Los Angeles in 1994 to support the city fire department, and has been enhanced and extended to hundreds of communities by FEMA to help citizens safely help each other in various emergencies.  &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The rewards are:&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Increased safety at your home &amp;amp; businessIncreased personal preparedness for windstorms, earthquakes and power outages New life-saving and first aid skillsIncreased self-confidence New friendsParticipation in the Vashon communityStylish green hard-hat and hi-vis vest (for team) &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Requirements to be on the active team: &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Vashon resident - full-time or part-time Very basic physical fitnessBasic CERT course (3 parts; see back of this flyer) Several additional Vashon-specific trainings (maps, two-way radios, a search exercise, etc.)Four refresher or enrichment trainings each year Comply with CERT policies and codes of conduct Favorable background check by VIFR Responsibility and accountability &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Typical activations include &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA; search for missing persons (Vashon has no other local search/rescue group), logistical support to the Fire Dept or Sheriff, information gathering during a disaster, and first aid. &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;CERT does not fight fires, go into unstable buildings, or neglect our own neighborhood. CERT members are specially trained to be a skilled resource in their neighborhoods, and respond to the greater community only after their own home and neighborhood are stable. &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;2017 Course Dates - &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;the program is offered at no cost to the public.  &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Options include:  &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The Five-Hour Preparedness Seminar on February 4  Another 20 hours of emergency response training for the average citizenEven more training to serve on the active Vashon CERT team. &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The 45 hour basic course covers: &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Safety training around utility problems such as gas leaks and damaged power linesReducing potential fire and electrical hazards in your home and business Extinguishing various types of small firesFirst aid including head-to-toe assessments, wound care, splinting, triage of multiple patients, and more Selecting and setting up a medical treatment area for a disaster situationHow to size-up various emergency situations and respond safely and effectivelySearching structures and the Vashon community or woods for lost personsHow Vashon&amp;rsquo;s CERT team operates, our responsibilities and coordinating with other organizations &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Supplemental topics and classes after joining the team: &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Use of two-way radios (both Ham radios and ordinary &amp;ldquo;walkie-talkies&amp;rdquo;) Reading various maps, finding addresses, using a compass and your phone to navigateThe nitty-gritty of supporting Vashon Fire Dept and County SheriffSeveral types of search operations and how to safely conduct each oneHow CERT partners with other citizen groups Advanced first aidAnd more&amp;hellip;the list is long and the topics are interesting &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;2017 Course Dates RSVP for any or all of these to: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:CERT@VashonBePrepared.org&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;CERT@VashonBePrepared.org&lt;/a&gt; CERT &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Manager Jan Milligan will send confirmation and, for the two longer segments, plenty of details about the curriculum, make- ups for sessions you might miss, team policies and more. Jan be reached by phone, 206-949-1184. Some info also at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vashonbeprepared.org/partners/CERT&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;www.vashonbeprepared.org/partners/CERT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;PART 1: 5 Hours of Basic Preparedness for you &amp;amp; your household - open to the public (February 4 at main fire station Farcy building, 9 a.m. to 2 p.m.) Bring a lunch or snacks; there will be no formal lunch break.&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;This session is sponsored by VashonBePrepared, with presenters from several citizen groups, Vashon Fire, and Puget Sound Energy &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;PART 2: 20 Hours of safety &amp;amp; emergency training in fire prevention, light fire fighting, utility safety, first aid for various situations, and light search &amp;amp; rescue. Five consecutive Friday evenings, 6- 10:00 p.m. at main fire station Farcy building. February 10, 17, 24 plus March 3 and 10. Pre-requisite: Feb 4 Preparedness seminar. You will need to provide a few inexpensive personal supplies: dust-mask, safety glasses, work clothes (grubbies) &amp;amp; gloves, and your own water/snacks. &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;PART 3: 20 Hours of CERT team operation - for those who want to join the active Vashon team, continue after Part 2 for three more Friday evenings (March 17, 24, 31) and Sunday March 26 for a disaster simulation, 8-4:00 (lunch provided that day). After completion, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn your green hard-hat and hi-vis vest. Pre- requisites are Parts 1 and 2. &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Vashon Island CERT is sponsored by Vashon Island Fire &amp;amp; Rescue&amp;hellip;.CERT is both a basic course and an active local team  &lt;br /&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;A partner of VashonBePrepared, the local network of citizen groups and government agencies dedicated to leading our island in preparedness and emergency response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change costs mount as natural catastrophe losses reach a 4 year high</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-01-04_entry396/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 16:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2017/2017-01-04_entry396/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./images/396/Windows-Live-Writer-6be8117698a8_7421-1-4-2017_at_8.25.05_AM_5.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;1-4-2017 at 8.25.05 AM&#34; style=&#34;border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px; background-image: none; border-bottom: 0px; float: right; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px; display: inline; padding-right: 0px&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;1-4-2017 at 8.25.05 AM&#34; src=&#34;./images/396/Windows-Live-Writer-6be8117698a8_7421-1-4-2017_at_8.25.05_AM_thumb_1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;441&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A number of devastating earthquakes and powerful storms made 2016 the costliest twelve months for natural catastrophe losses in the last four years. Losses totaled US$ 175bn, a good two-thirds more than in the previous year, and very nearly as high as the figure for 2012 (US$ 180bn). The share of uninsured losses – the so-called protection or insurance gap – remained substantial at around 70%. Almost 30% of the losses, some US$ 50bn, were insured.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
