<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 20:22:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FEMA Releases 2021 National Preparedness Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-12-21_entry482/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 20:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-12-21_entry482/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fema.gov/sites/default/files/documents/fema_2021-national-preparedness-report-executive-summary.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;353&#34; height=&#34;449&#34; title=&#34;National Preparedness Report- Executive Summary&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;National Preparedness Report- Executive Summary&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/482/Open-Live-Writer-01f4caf279ff_ACCD-National_Preparedness_Report-_Executive_Summary_8c134699-cfd3-4834-b4e2-5b74448aeee2.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;FEMA released the 10th annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/national-preparedness#reports&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2021 National Preparedness Report (NPR).&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FEMA and KIRO-AM Seattle Unveil New Emergency Broadcast Studio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-11-19_entry481/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 03:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-11-19_entry481/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEATTLE — Together, FEMA and Bonneville Seattle have completed an important modernization at the emergency radio broadcast facility at Bonneville International’s KIRO-AM 710 in Seattle. This modernization project improves emergency alert systems that provide critical alerts and warnings to the public.&lt;p&gt;The KIRO-AM facility serves as a Primary Entry Point (PEP) station for FEMA’s National Public Warning System (NPWS), maintained under FEMA’s Integrated Public Alert and Warning System (IPAWS), and provides critical information to the public before, during and after incidents and disasters.&lt;p&gt;Under the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act enacted in 2015, Congress required FEMA to upgrade PEP stations across the country to ensure continuity of terrestrial broadcast services under all hazards. PEP stations are specially designated NPWS broadcast stations that serve as the primary intake source of initial broadcasts for a national alert. FEMA equips these stations, which are operated by local station personnel, with backup communications equipment and power generators that enable them to continue broadcasting information to the public during and after an emergency, including conveying official alerts to communities regionally and nationwide. These free-standing emergency studios, located at the radio transmitter sites, are specially designed and hardened to withstand various natural disasters and acts of terrorism. This helps ensure that the President can alert and warn the public under all conditions. Currently, there are 77 PEP stations that are capable of reaching 90 percent of the U.S. population.&lt;p&gt;KIRO-AM is the 14th PEP station to complete the all-hazards upgrade. The modernization to the emergency studio includes increased sheltering capabilities, expanded broadcast capacity, and sustainable power generation for all types of hazardous events, increasing KIRO-AM’s resiliency to continue broadcasting during emergencies.&lt;p&gt;“It’s an honor for Bonneville Seattle to serve the community and we are proud to partner with FEMA. We share and salute the agency’s commitment to protecting the public,” said Darrell Brown, President, Bonneville International. “Radio is a lifeline, and the new studio and continued investment will ensure KIRO-AM 710’s resiliency during times of crisis when communication is vital.”&lt;p&gt;&#34;For generations, the KIRO-AM signal has been designated by the federal government as the one to broadcast critical information in case of a major disaster,&#34; said Cathy Cangiano, Senior VP/Market Manager, Bonneville Seattle. &#34;It&#39;s a responsibility we take seriously. We are committed to getting out lifesaving information when our region needs us.&#34;&lt;p&gt;If required, and in a national worst-case scenario, KIRO-AM would broadcast a message from the President or other national authorities within 10 minutes. Via FEMA’s Emergency Alert System, other radio stations in the Seattle area would begin re-broadcasting the information coming from KIRO and its news staff. Local authorities, such as the King County Office of Emergency Management, may also disseminate life-saving information by way of the new facilities installed at the KIRO tower site.&lt;p&gt;FEMA, KIRO and King County are partners in distributing life-saving emergency information to the public.&lt;p&gt;FEMA and Bonneville Seattle will hold an event on Friday, November 19, 2021, (11 a.m. to 1 p.m. PT) to unveil the upgraded KIRO-AM transmitter and PEP Site (22805 Dockton Road SW, Vashon, WA 98070.) The news conference will include FEMA and local officials, as well as a live demonstration from KIRO-AM 710 on-air hosts.&lt;p&gt;Speakers include:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Antwane Johnson, Director, Integrated Public Alert and Warning System, FEMA &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manny Centeno, IPAWS Program Manager, FEMA &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brendan McCluskey, Director, King County Office of Emergency Management &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jason Shirron, Technical Operations Coordinator, King County OEM &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vince Maykovich, Acting Regional Administrator, FEMA Region 10 &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cathy Cangiano, VP/Market Manager, Bonneville Seattle &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jason Ornellas, Regional Director of Engineering, Bonneville International West Region &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dave Ross, On-Air Host, KIRO Radio 97.3 FM &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about IPAWS or the PEP modernization effort, go to FEMA’s website at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/practitioners/integrated-public-alert-warning-system/broadcasters-wireless&#34;&gt;https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/practitioners/integrated-public-alert-warning-&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/practitioners/integrated-public-alert-warning-system/broadcasters-wireless&#34;&gt;system/broadcasters-wireless. &lt;/a&gt;To learn more about Bonneville Seattle and KIRO-AM 710 Seattle, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://bonneville.com/our-markets/seattle/&#34;&gt;https://bonneville.com/our-markets/seattle/.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KCSO launches new phone app</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-09-04_entry479/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 04:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-09-04_entry479/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width=&#34;643&#34; valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/king-county-sheriffs-office-launches-new-phone-app&#34;&gt;https://www.kiro7.com/news/local/king-county-sheriffs-office-launches-new-phone-app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;KING COUNTY, Wash. — Community members in King County will now be able to submit tips, access inmate information, research sex offenders in their area and more with just a click away on their smartphones.&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, King County Sheriff Mitzi G. Johanknecht announced a new smartphone app for the King County Sheriff’s Office.&lt;p&gt;The app will help connect the community with the sheriff’s office and send out information to anyone with a smartphone.&lt;p&gt;“Open and accurate communication are the fundamentals of transparency, which in turn builds trust with the communities we serve,” said Johanknecht. “Our new mobile app gives us a better way to alert, inform and prepare the public. We even have weather alerts.”&lt;p&gt;The app provides access to information of public interest:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Submit a tip &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meet the Sheriff &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Access COVID-19 resources &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Receive push notifications &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Connect to the organization’s social media platforms &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read the latest news and updates &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Access inmate information &#xA;&lt;li&gt;Research sex offenders in the area &#xA;&lt;li&gt;And more &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The free app is available for both Android and Apple users.&lt;p&gt;Users who want to download the app can find it in the App Store and Google Play by searching “King Sheriff WA” or &lt;a href=&#34;https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA5MDIuNDU0MDM4OTEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL2FwcHMubXlvY3YuY29tL3NoYXJlL2E1MTU5ODEwNCJ9.O_gQVtbHt78CE5LHa-tcP5m3kFvtxsVm5alRay4a368/s/45829802/br/111800705108-l__;!!F8-Dj6fVkZI!NimnRfLrzWR5mx8rF0GejpdmY9RYG4Q6RKzE_vlZhxlU1GgKoGXB3IUbOAYL1GM$&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1-- Make A Plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-09-01_entry478/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-09-01_entry478/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;317&#34; height=&#34;317&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;https://www.ready.gov/sites/default/files/2021-08/ready_npm_instagram_spanish.png&#34; src=&#34;https://www.ready.gov/sites/default/files/2021-08/ready_npm_instagram_spanish.png&#34;&gt;This week focuses on making an emergency plan. You are encouraged to do the following this week:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FEMA Kicks Off National Preparedness Month, Urging Americans to ‘Prepare to Protect’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-31_entry477/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 19:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-31_entry477/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Each September, FEMA’s Ready Campaign uses this time to encourage people to take steps to prepare for disasters and emergencies that could happen anywhere and at any time. This year’s theme is “&lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDYsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy53aGl0ZWhvdXNlLmdvdi9icmllZmluZy1yb29tL3ByZXNpZGVudGlhbC1hY3Rpb25zLzIwMjEvMDgvMzEvYS1wcm9jbGFtYXRpb24tb24tbmF0aW9uYWwtcHJlcGFyZWRuZXNzLW1vbnRoLTIwMjEvIn0.06eE4fdXvDgd1dFloHKikzD-ybvQX3dJ0f6O06RR4y8/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Prepare to Protect&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preparing for disasters is protecting everyone you love. Act now to prepare yourself and your family before disaster strikes.&lt;p&gt;Throughout the month, weekly themes will be used to highlight basic preparedness activities that everyone can do, including:&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;· Week 1, Sept. 1-4: Make A Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;· Week 2, Sept. 5-11: Build A Kit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;· Week 3, Sept. 12-18: Low-Cost, No-Cost Preparedness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;· Week 4, Sept. 19-25: Teach Children about Preparedness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow FEMA on &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDcsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5mYWNlYm9vay5jb20vcmVhZHlnb3YvIn0.YX7MvC-1GB0YCW77up2imyHH9LWI5BlEiojzPfkJwTQ/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDgsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL3JlYWR5Z292LyJ9.fNJ8w3l5N_V-rxJ6vGTpE88lMhGYaDLVgbgmh3WPHRI/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMDksInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5pbnN0YWdyYW0uY29tL2ZlbWEvIn0.MAyz_DLHfgmb93q07SqVENgJahZPyNEskKA0exOSqIk/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, and share posts about preparedness. In addition, the Ready Campaign has developed a &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTAsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5yZWFkeS5nb3YvbmF0aW9uYWwtcHJlcGFyZWRuZXNzLW1vbnRoLXNvY2lhbC1tZWRpYS10b29sa2l0In0.F6mqi_lQpN3rNRpW4KIgWEkRU3LP66L62-oNtGZYGpc/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;toolkit&lt;/a&gt; for creating content for social media posts.&lt;p&gt;Later this month, the Ready Campaign and the Ad Council will launch a series of PSAs aimed at family and personal preparedness efforts. This year, the campaign will specifically feature the Latino/Hispanic demographic to ensure campaign messages are culturally competent and meeting the needs of historically underserved populations.&lt;p&gt;Remember to use #&lt;strong&gt;PreparetoProtect&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;#BeReady &lt;/strong&gt;hashtags with a mention to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTEsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3R3aXR0ZXIuY29tL3JlYWR5Z292In0.-E_5HI2ruyfPR_IIOpA6xLDODP8QAVL-eZFhp9K6nns/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Ready Campaign&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnks.gd/l/eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJidWxsZXRpbl9saW5rX2lkIjoxMTIsInVyaSI6ImJwMjpjbGljayIsImJ1bGxldGluX2lkIjoiMjAyMTA4MzEuNDUyOTgxODEiLCJ1cmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5yZWFkeS5nb3Yvc2VwdGVtYmVyIn0.bHglmuEqMuJhcenWL7qzuIBI5t3H0zch9stNby8xkgo/s/38437761/br/111666035914-l&#34;&gt;Ready.gov/September&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;590&#34; height=&#34;590&#34; alt=&#34;NPM&#34; src=&#34;https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USDHSFEMA/2021/08/4830256/npm_original.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid high temperatures and dry conditions, King County Fire Marshal issues Stage 2 burn ban prohibiting outdoor recreational fires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-13_entry476/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 21:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-13_entry476/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5&gt;King County Fire Marshal Chris Ricketts has issued a Stage 2 burn ban for unincorporated King County, which prohibits all outdoor recreational fires. Outdoor cooking and heating appliances are restricted to approved manufactured gas and charcoal units only.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Stage 2 burn ban goes into effect immediately for King County, which was &lt;a href=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/local-services/news/2021/20210623-fire-safety-burn-ban.aspx&#34;&gt;already in a Stage 1 burn ban&lt;/a&gt;. King County’s ban is in coordination with the King County Fire Chiefs Association and Fire Marshals, which extends the ban into cities.&lt;p&gt;During a Stage 2 burn ban, any outdoor fire such as a backyard fire pit or campfire using chopped firewood or charcoal is prohibited. Under the ban, any person with a recreational fire who fails to take immediate action to extinguish or discontinue when ordered or notified to do so can be charged with, up to and including, a misdemeanor.&lt;p&gt;Manufactured portable outdoor devices are allowed, including barbeques and patio warmers that are used in accordance with the manufacturer’s instructions. Approved fuel devices - including those that rely on charcoal, natural gas or propane gas – are also allowed. Ricketts asks residents to please use caution when disposing of charcoal remains.&lt;p&gt;Extended periods of abnormally high temperatures have increased the fuel load in the vegetation in our community. The large fire in Oregon and other fires in Washington have stretched wildfire fighting resources throughout the region.&lt;p&gt;Ricketts says if residents must smoke, they should exercise extreme caution with their ashes or when they’re extinguishing cigarettes. The county asks residents to be diligent and respectful of their neighbors, and to remember this is a demanding time for first responders.&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;LINKS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/local-services/permits/fire-safety/burn-bans-fireworks.aspx&#34;&gt;King County Burn Ban &amp;amp; Fireworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vashon expected to get smoky–as well as hot for next few days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-12_entry475/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 23:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-12_entry475/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to Cliff Mass, we’ve smoke in our future, at least thru Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vashon COVID Update Delta Wave of COVID Has Taken Hold on Vashon Vaccination Has Been Working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-10_entry474/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 03:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-08-10_entry474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width=&#34;100%&#34; valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vashon COVID Update: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Delta Wave of COVID Has Taken Hold on Vashon -- &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for wildfire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-29_entry473/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-29_entry473/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;House with fire resistant landscaping&#34; src=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/~/media/environment/waterland/forestry/images/FirewiseHouse.ashx?w=262&amp;amp;h=182&amp;amp;as=1&amp;amp;la=en&#34;&gt;Even in temperate western Washington it can take only a few sunny days for forests to dry out enough to catch fire. And, in windy conditions wildfires can get out of control quickly. Wildfires burn every year in east King County. Before wildfire strikes, homeowners can help protect lives and property by creating a fire-adapted space around structures.&lt;h3&gt;Top 8 tips for maintaining a wildfire safety zone in the 30 feet around your home&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove all dead plant material from around your home. Rake up dry leaves (under decks and porches too!) and move firewood away from the house. Keep your roof and gutters clear of flammable debris.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Place a 3 to 5-foot swath of gravel or stones around the foundation of your home instead of flammable mulch.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prune branches that overhang or touch the house. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take out &#34;ladder fuels,&#34; vegetation between grass and treetops that can carry fire between foliage and structures.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep blowing embers out of your house. Cover exterior vents with fine (1/8-inch) mesh. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Store flammable materials, including cushions, indoors instead of on porches and decks.&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use fire-resistant construction materials such as Class-A asphalt shingles, metal or concrete products for your roof. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use fire-resistant plants in the garden. Read our list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://your.kingcounty.gov/dnrp/library/water-and-land/forestry/forestfire/FirewisePlantsPugetSoundBasin-2011.pdf&#34;&gt;fire-resistant plants for the Puget Sound Basin&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), or search our illustrated online &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://green2.kingcounty.gov/gonative/index.aspx&#34;&gt;Native Plant Guide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;for fire-resistant plants. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Copied from &lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/services/environment/water-and-land/forestry/forestfire.aspx&#34; href=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/services/environment/water-and-land/forestry/forestfire.aspx&#34;&gt;https://kingcounty.gov/services/environment/water-and-land/forestry/forestfire.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;– which has MORE details and information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington State Free Drive-In Wi-Fi Hotspots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-21_entry471/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-21_entry471/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;394&#34; height=&#34;243&#34; title=&#34;image&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/471/Open-Live-Writer-Washington-State-Drive-In-WiFi-Hotspots_EC8E-image_ba5f4ff7-341b-40d6-a962-55c885be142a.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;In response to the impacts of COVID-19, &lt;em&gt;Drive-In Wi-Fi Hotspots &lt;/em&gt;provide free temporary, emergency internet access for Washingtonians who do not have broadband service to their homes.&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washington Wi-Fi Finder:&lt;br&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;https://www.commerce.wa.gov/building-infrastructure/washington-state-drive-in-wifi-hotspots-location-finder/&#34; href=&#34;https://www.commerce.wa.gov/building-infrastructure/washington-state-drive-in-wifi-hotspots-location-finder/&#34;&gt;https://www.commerce.wa.gov/building-infrastructure/washington-state-drive-in-wifi-hotspots-location-finder/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seattle High Tide Flooding Probability Scenarios Through 2100</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-17_entry470/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-17_entry470/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;464&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; title=&#34;image&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://vashonbeprepared.org./images/470/Open-Live-Writer-71caef80086b_B2D2-image_f7e3f2c1-e7e3-4f7a-a76a-a77eb4e66ae5.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;A new web application from ESRI provides a nice visual overlay to the latest ocean flooding scenarios – including&#xA;  Seattle and by inference, Vashon too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID Update-- Vashon Records First Known &#34;Breakthrough&#34; Case in Vaccinated Patient</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-14_entry469/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 21:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-14_entry469/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;416&#34; height=&#34;217&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;Number of Reported COVID Cases Among Fully Vaccinated Continues to Climb &amp;bull; Children&#39;s Health Defense&#34; src=&#34;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftse2.mm.bing.net%2Fth%3Fid%3DOIF.dQkCQpf5tjv%252bCY8N0l0eeA%26pid%3DApi&amp;amp;f=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please DO NOT Have a Blast, Vashon!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-03_entry468/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 03:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-07-03_entry468/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/Portals/1/Graphics/Fire/FireSafety_FireworksEmailable_2021-07-02.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;335&#34; height=&#34;474&#34; title=&#34;Prevent Vashon Wildfires&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;Prevent Vashon Wildfires&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/Portals/1/Graphics/Fire/FireSafety_FireworksEmailable_2021-07-02.jpg&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Weather Update–Mon June 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-28_entry467/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 15:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-28_entry467/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;406&#34; height=&#34;208&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;Keeping your cool in hot weather | News And Information | Oklahoma State University&#34; src=&#34;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftse1.mm.bing.net%2Fth%3Fid%3DOIP.QqpmciJ6NkCinVU9RfKANQHaDz%26pid%3DApi&amp;amp;f=1&#34;&gt;Weather forecasters predict today will be hotter than yesterday and likely to set new records for high temperatures, the highest ever experienced in the Puget Sound area, including Vashon. Vashon will hit a high of well over 100 degrees with the National Weather Service suggesting the possibility of a high temperature on Vashon of 112 degrees.&lt;p&gt;Three air conditioned cooling center locations are available today on Vashon, open from 10:00am to 6:00pm. Masks and social distancing are required. Here are the three locations...&lt;p&gt; - Vashon Library, in town at 17210 Vashon Highway, at Ober Park.&lt;p&gt;In addition, VashonBePrepared has arranged for two more cooling centers where free water or soft drinks are being provided.&lt;p&gt; - The lobby of Vashon Center for the Arts, south of town at 19600 Vashon Highway at the intersection with Cemetery Road.&lt;br&gt; - Subway restaurant, in town at 17408 Vashon Highway one block north of the intersection with Bank Road.&lt;p&gt;If you need transportation to reach the cooling centers, arrange a trip by contacting Vashon Community Van at 206-263-5901 or email &lt;a&gt;communityvan@kingcounty.gov&lt;/a&gt;, or go online to:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/local-services/programs/vashon-community-van.aspx&#34; href=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/local-services/programs/vashon-community-van.aspx&#34;&gt;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/local-services/programs/vashon-community-van.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the cooling centers, here are some heat safety tips from Public Health -- Seattle &amp;amp; King County and VashonBePrepared....&lt;p&gt; - Minimize physical exertion and do outdoor activities during the cooler morning hours.&lt;p&gt; - Stay in the shade and keep sipping a cool non-alcoholic drink. Water is best.&lt;p&gt; - Don&#39;t leave people or pets in the car, even with the windows rolled down.&lt;p&gt; - Wear light, loose, breathable clothing, preferably cotton.&lt;p&gt; - Check on others, to spot and respond to any signs of heat illness, such as nausea and confusion, dry hot flushed skin, and rapid pulse. &lt;p&gt; - Practice water safety by using personal flotation devices, and remember the sunscreen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vashon Community Cooling Centers–Updated 6/26/21 AM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-26_entry466/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 14:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-26_entry466/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;Anaheim cooling centers open during heat wave | Orange County Breeze&#34; src=&#34;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftse2.mm.bing.net%2Fth%3Fid%3DOIP.R-tAQBpkA5k49NJ2--UY8AHaC4%26pid%3DApi&amp;amp;f=1&#34;&gt;An extended heat wave is affecting Vashon and the rest of the Puget Sound this weekend with&amp;nbsp; high temperatures that could exceed 110 degrees by Monday.&lt;p&gt;Three air conditioned cooling center locations are available on Vashon, open from 10:00am to 6:00pm each day. Masks and social distancing are required.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The lobby of &lt;strong&gt;Vashon Center for the Arts&lt;/strong&gt;, south of town at 19600 Vashon Highway at the intersection with Cemetery Road. Open all three days, through Monday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subway restaurant&lt;/strong&gt;, in town at 17408 Vashon Highway one block north of the intersection with Bank Road. Open all three days, through Monday.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vashon Library&lt;/strong&gt;, in town at 17210 Vashon Highway, at Ober Park. Open Saturday and Monday, closed Sunday.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you need transportation to reach the cooling centers, arrange a trip by contacting Vashon Community Van at 206-263-5901 or email &lt;a&gt;communityvan@kingcounty.gov&lt;/a&gt;, or go online to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Water Wisely This Summer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry464/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 23:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry464/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img width=&#34;319&#34; height=&#34;319&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;10 Ways To Conserve Water - Save Water on Earth - DON&#39;T WASTE !! Initiate With Me&#34; src=&#34;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftse1.mm.bing.net%2Fth%3Fid%3DOIP.e6GwOdDJ4mkoktycubgOKgHaHa%26pid%3DApi&amp;amp;f=1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;... and all year long!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vashon Cooling Centers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry463/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 21:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry463/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;197&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; alt=&#34;Social Services | Prince George&#39;s County, MD&#34; src=&#34;https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Ftse1.mm.bing.net%2Fth%3Fid%3DOIP.RICHIWwX7OoyRTd8egHTjwAAAA%26pid%3DApi&amp;amp;f=1&#34;&gt;There are two air conditioned cooling center locations on Vashon Island, open from 10:00am to 6:00pm, Saturday through Monday. Masks and social distancing are required at both of these locations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest from the National Weather Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry462/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry462/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning’s briefings included these slides that may be of interest…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>June’s Record Heat Wave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry461/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-06-25_entry461/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;383&#34; height=&#34;371&#34; title=&#34;King County Heat Map for this weekend shows a wide variance in temeratures through out the King County. Unfortunately, the county still sometimes forgets about us on Vashon Island!&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline; background-image: none;&#34; alt=&#34;King_County_Heat_Map&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/portals/1/Graphics/WebSite/King_County_Heat_Map.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;An extended heat wave will affect Vashon and the rest of the Puget Sound this weekend with&amp;nbsp; high temperatures above 105 degrees predicted Sunday and Monday.&lt;p&gt;Heat waves can be dangerous for elders, infants, people on medications, and people with health conditions that increase heat sensitivity, so it&#39;s important to take sensible precautions to avoid heat-related illness. &lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to beat the heat from Public Health -- Seattle &amp;amp; King County and VashonBePrepared....&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Minimize physical exertion and do outdoor activities during the cooler morning hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Stay in the shade and keep sipping a cool non-alcoholic drink. Water is best.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Don&#39;t leave people or pets in the car, even with the windows rolled down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Wear light, loose, breathable clothing, preferably cotton.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Check on others, to spot and respond to any signs of heat illness, such as nausea and confusion, dry hot flushed skin, and rapid pulse. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Practice water safety by using personal flotation devices, and remember the sunscreen.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Few people in our area have air conditioning but you can improvise. You can make a simple evaporative cooler -- like a swamp cooler -- by draping a wet towel over a chair and aiming your fan at it so the cooled air blows your way. Remoisten the towel when it gets too dry to make cool air. &lt;p&gt;See the hot weather blog at Public Health Seattle - King County for more tips to beat the heat.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/health/emergency-preparedness/preparing-yourself/hot-weather.aspx&#34;&gt;https://kingcounty.gov/depts/health/emergency-preparedness/preparing-yourself/hot-weather.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Amendment to the state Good Samaritan Law</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-04-29_entry460/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 14:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-04-29_entry460/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Washington Governor Jay Inslee signed a new amendment into law on Tuesday, and it will take effect 7/25/21. &lt;p&gt;Here’s the link to the formal wording and the RCW citation for future reference. &lt;a href=&#34;http://lawfilesext.leg.wa.gov/biennium/2021-22/Pdf/Bills/Session%20Laws/House/1209-S.SL.pdf#page=1&#34;&gt;http://lawfilesext.leg.wa.gov/biennium/2021-22/Pdf/Bills/Session%20Laws/House/1209-S.SL.pdf#page=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember this is the section that applies to people helping their neighbors in a “it’s a disaster” situation, not the people who have protections as a Registered Emergency Worker (their coverage is in a different section).&lt;p&gt;Our appreciation to West Seattle Be Prepared neighbor Cindi Barker for her efforts to get this passed in this year’s busy legislative session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Tsunami Maps for Puget Sound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-04-27_entry459/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 17:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-04-27_entry459/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&lt;a title=&#34;Click for larger version&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/Portals/1/Graphics//Tsunami/gger_ms2021-01_tsunami_hazard_maps_puget_sound_map_sheet_13_georeferenced_eastern_south_sound_current_speed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;271&#34; height=&#34;158&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 4px; float: right;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/portals/1/Graphics/Tsunami/ger_ms2021-01_tsunami_hazard_maps_puget_sound_map_sheet_13_georeferenced_eastern_south_sound_current_speed%20(Small).png&#34;&gt;&#xA;Click map for a larger version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of disasters and crises on agriculture and food security-- 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-03-23_entry458/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-03-23_entry458/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/cb3673en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px; border-image: none; float: right; display: inline;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.fao.org/3/cb3673en/cb3673en_200.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A new report from the Food &amp;amp; Agriculture Organization of the United Nations paints a somber picture for agrarian communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington Good Samaritan law</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-03-19_entry457/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 17:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-03-19_entry457/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Washington Good Samaritan law protects the general public during some activities even outside declared emergencies. Some aspects of the law are being reconsidered:&lt;p&gt;The current Washington State Good Samaritan Law covers only medical aid given in times of a disaster. There is no provision for the general population to have Good Samaritan protection should they want to help their neighbors in the response to a significant event outside of a clear medical context.&lt;p&gt;In 2021, a new bill has been sponsored to add an addition to the existing law and is currently moving through the House. The requested addition extends the existing law to include non-medical aid given in times of disaster. &lt;p&gt;Important note: this would be beneficial in response to all hazards, including flooding, landslides, and wildfires, and is not specific only to an earthquake scenario.&lt;p&gt;Key Points:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emergency Managers throughout the State of Washington work to help their residents prepare for disaster and build community resilience as their resources will be overwhelmed in a major disaster. &#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Good Samaritan Law as written currently covers only medical assistance. In a major disaster, if neighbors are going to help neighbors, as is promoted by emergency management across the state, then the state should extend the law and its liability coverage to those volunteers. &#xA;&lt;li&gt;CERT programs, medical and first responders, as well other emergency worker volunteer teams will NOT be affected by this change, and will provide those teams with more willing and protected people who will help them in a disaster. &#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is precedent by other States for this addition to the Good Samaritan Law. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To read the bill (HB1209) and track its progress: &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.leg.wa.gov/billsummary?BillNumber=1209&amp;amp;Year=2021&amp;amp;Initiative=False&#34;&gt;Washington State Legislature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;To write a testimony in support: &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.leg.wa.gov/pbc/bill/1209&#34;&gt;https://app.leg.wa.gov/pbc/bill/1209&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Seattle Be Prepared&#39;s Cindi Barker is a local resource for more information on this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Earthquake Early Warning System Test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-02-23_entry456/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2021/2021-02-23_entry456/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;251&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; style=&#34;float: right; display: inline;&#34; src=&#34;https://mil.wa.gov/asset/6011a812aa2ce&#34;&gt;For this Sunday’s 20th anniversary of the Nisqually Earthquake, the University of Washington has created created a simulation based on that historic quake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
