<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020-5-26 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2020-5-26/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020-5-26 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 22:39:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2020-5-26/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chamber of Commerce offers 15 Re-Opening Workshops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2020/2020-05-26_entry450/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 22:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2020/2020-05-26_entry450/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;· &lt;i&gt;Registration has started for &lt;b&gt;reopening workshops&lt;/b&gt; being put on by the Chamber of Commerce. Fifteen of the workshops have been scheduled over the next two weeks. They are &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;designed to aid local businesses and organizations &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;open up under the Phase 2 safety conditions set by the Governor. The planning workshops will help businesses &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;reduce risk to staff, ensure customers feel safe and secure, and give &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;business operators confidence that they are &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;following best practices to protect our community’s health. The free workshops are offered by Vashon Chamber of Commerce and &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;are being funded by &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;VashonBePrepared.  Each participant will receive a toolkit that will including masks (provided by Masks for Vashon), sanitizer, floor signs for six foot distancing, and signage for the establishment&#39;s safety commitments.  One option in the free toolkit will be plexiglass sneeze shields fabricated by volunteers from the Makerspace/Tool Library group.  Visit &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vashonchamber.com/re-opening-round-tables/&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;https://www.vashonchamber.com/re-opening-round-tables/&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;to sign up for one of the workshops:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;o &lt;i&gt;In-Home Services and Constructions, Thursdays May 28, Jun 4, and Jun 11 at 4pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;o &lt;i&gt;Body Workers, Hair and Nail Salons, Grooming and Tattoo Artists, Mondays Jun1, Jun 8 and Jun 15 at noon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;o &lt;i&gt;Merchants, Galleries, Artists and Non-Essential Retail, Thursdays May 28, Jun 4, and Jun 11 at 9am&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;o &lt;i&gt;Recreation &amp;amp; Fitness, Fridays Jun 5, Jun 12 and Jun 19 at 9am.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Restaurants, Bars and Beverages, Mon Jun 1, Thurs Jun 4 and Wed Jun 8 all at 10am&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
