<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2010-7 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2010-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2010-7 on eoc.online - Insights &amp; Resources for EOCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 19:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/archive/2010-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FCC Rules that Amateurs May Participate in Non-Government-Sponsored Drills by Employers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2010/2010-07-17_entry16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 19:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2010/2010-07-17_entry16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;em&gt;Report and Order&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hraunfoss.fcc.gov/edocs_public/attachmatch/FCC-10-124A1.pdf&#34;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&gt;R&amp;amp;O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) released Wednesday, July 14, the FCC stated that under new guidelines, amateurs employed by non-governmental agencies, such as hospitals, may participate and operate in drills sponsored by their employer. Specifically, the FCC will now permit Amateur Radio operators &amp;ldquo;to transmit messages, under certain limited circumstances, during either government-sponsored or non-government sponsored emergency and disaster preparedness drills, regardless of whether the operators are employees of entities participating in the drill.&amp;rdquo; More information will be posted on the ARRL Web site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEALTH ADVISORY-- Safety During Excessive Heat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2010/2010-07-08_entry14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oconline.github.io/insights/2010/2010-07-08_entry14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Cross Encourages Safety During Excessive Heat American Red Cross&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As the temperature continues to increase as it is predicted to this week, the American Red Cross encourages individuals and families to take the necessary precautions for excessive heat.  The very young and the elderly are especially vulnerable to the heat so it is important that families and friends check on them regularly.  People with chronic health issues are also at greater risk and need to take special care to stay healthy in the heat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
